# Thomas Bergmanis | BSc

Email: tom.bergmanis@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thomas-bergmanis-540262171

GitHub: https://github.com/TomBergmanis

Mobile: 07553 160058

#### **PROFILE:**

Experienced Acoustic Engineer with over 3 years in the field, aspiring to use my relevant skills to transition into a tech role. Actively learning Python and JavaScript. Applying this knowledge to streamline processes in my current role. I am committed to continuous learning and I aspire to contribute to your company's growth and success.

#### **TECH STACK:**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Tools: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Git, GitHub, Command Line

# **KEY SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES:**

- ✓ Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook etc)
- ✓ Strong problem-solving and critical thinking skills.
- ✓ Collaborative team player with a client-focused approach.
- ✓ Self-motivated and proactive in taking initiative.
- ✓ Strong appetite to learn and improve.
- ✓ Exceptional written and verbal communication skills.
- ✓ Effective communication with technical and non-technical stakeholders.

#### **EDUCATION:**

- Postgraduate Diploma in Noise and Vibration Control, Institute of Acoustics, Jan 2022
- Bachelor of Science in Music Technology, Birmingham City University, Jul 2020 (First-Class)
   Dissertation (Final Year Project) nominated for the Innovation Fest 2020. Presented my project to field experts and businesses.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# Product Tester – Jenson8 [Jan 2024 - Present] Freelance

- Test proprietary virtual reality software within a team of product testers, effectively communicating back errors or issues to the product development team. Taking into consideration the details to maximise user immersive experience.
- Additional duties; conduct product demonstration days with clients and act as a point for technical support.
- Clients: HSBC, Johnson & Johnson, Bank of America, DELL, Nestle, GSK, EDF etc.

# Graduate Acoustic Consultant - Auricl Acoustic Consulting [Apr 2022 to Present]

- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to evaluate and assist in designing and completing large and small construction projects (RIBA Stages 0-7) and have completed over 150 projects during service to Auricl.
- Utilise expertise in working with complex data sets to create meaningful insights and solutions for client projects.
- Creation of Excel templates to streamline and enhance day-to-day processes.
- Act as a point of contact for internal colleagues and external clients, to provide technical support and resolve
  inquiries with a customer-centric approach.
- Working on multiple projects at once and making sure they are delivered on time and to a high standard.

# Assistant Acoustic Consultant – Adnitt Acoustic Consulting [Dec 2020 to Apr 2022]

- Collecting and processing large data sets, presenting the findings within detailed reports for internal colleagues and external clients.
- Implemented new key functionality to an existing software system that streamlines data-processing and analysis improving data analysis efficiency by 15%.

# **CERTIFICATES / ACHIEVEMENTS:**

- Python Software Engineering, HyperionDev/CoGrammar, Mar 2024 Grade 99%
- JavaScript Foundation, The Odin Project, Nov 2023